<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="yes"?>
<ModMetaData>
  <name>Mod Manager</name>
  <author>Fluffy</author>
  <url>https://ludeon.com/forums/index.php?topic=16120</url>
  <description>Managing mods should be easy!

&lt;size=24&gt;Features&lt;/size&gt;
A cleaner, better Mod management screen.


separate lists for available and active mods
create and delete local copies of steam mods
create and load mod list backups
load mod list from save games
(mass) subscribe to steam mods
proper search filtering
drag and drop activation and reordering
keyboard navigation
mod and mod list colouring
discover other mods by your favourite author(s)

And, if supported by the mod author;


version checking
dependency checks
incompatibility checks
load order hints

&lt;size=24&gt;For Modders&lt;/size&gt;
Allows modders to create a Manifest.xml file, enabling a bunch of features that should have been in vanilla;


version checking
dependency checking
incompatibility checking
load order hints

See the documentation for details on how to implement this. It’s easy!



&lt;size=24&gt;Details&lt;/size&gt;
&lt;b&gt;local mod copies&lt;/b&gt;You can make a local copy of any steam mods (or all active steam mods at once) by clicking the corresponding button underneath the mod details (or active mods list). Doing this will make sure any updates to the steam version will not break your game in progress. Local mods are created in the RimWorld/Mods folder, and can be manually deleted, or deleted by clicking the corresponding button underneath the mod details.

&lt;i&gt;Note: You may want to occasionally delete obsolete local copies, as having many mods in the mod folder will make RimWorld take longer to start, and the Mod Manager window take longer to open.&lt;/i&gt;

&lt;b&gt;mod list backups&lt;/b&gt;You can create mod lists by clicking the mod list button underneath your active mods, and selecting ‘save current list’. You will have to choose a unique name, and the mod list will be stored in a folder next to your save games. 
To load a modlist, click the mod list button, then select the save game or mod list you want to load mods from. Any mods that couldn’t be matched to your current list of mods will be greyed out. 
To delete a mod list (only the list, not the actual mods), click the mod list button, select the list to be deleted, and then choose the delete option.

&lt;b&gt;steam subscribing&lt;/b&gt;
If a loaded modlist contains mods you do not have installed, but are available on the workshop, you can quickly install the mod by clicking the button in the mod details. You can also click the ‘subscribe to all’ button underneath the active mods list to subscribe to all missing mods.

&lt;b&gt;mod and mod list colours&lt;/b&gt;
You can set colours for individual mods by clicking the palette icon underneath the mod details. To change the colour for all mods in a mod list, click the mod list icon underneat the active mod list, select the list, then ‘change colour’.

&lt;b&gt;keyboard navigation&lt;/b&gt;Sometimes, it’s easier to navigate large lists with the keyboard.


Tab: cycles focus between search inputs and lists of mods.
Up/Down: selects the previous/next mod in the list.
Page Up/Down: selects the top/bottom mod in the list.
Left/Right: switch focus between active and available lists. 

You can also manipulate the lists;


Enter: activates/deactivates a mod, and selects the next mod in the list.
Shift+left: deactivates a mod, keeping it selected, and switching focus to the available list.
Shift+right: activates a mod, keeping it selected, and switching focus to the active list.
Shift+up/Shift+down: move an active mod up/down in the load order.
Shift+Page Up/Down: move an active mod to the top/bottom of the load order.

&lt;b&gt;mod promotions&lt;/b&gt;
When a Steam Workshop mod is selected (or a local copy of a steam workshop mod), Mod Manager will automatically look for other mods by the same author, and show you a promotion for any mods you don’t already have. These promotions let you easily discover other (new) mods by your favourite author(s), and even quickly subscribe to them!

&lt;i&gt;This function can be turned off in Mod Managers’ settings&lt;/i&gt;



&lt;size=24&gt;Contributors&lt;/size&gt;

erdelf:    invaluable help with Harmony transpilers
Brrainz:    multi-version targetting, inspiration for mod promotions
b606:    French translation
Proxyer:    Japanese translation
奔跑的梅洛斯:    Simplified Chinese translation
Zetrith:    Fix blurry mod descriptions
enescaglayan:    Turkish translation

&lt;size=24&gt;Version&lt;/size&gt;
This is version 1.31.872, for RimWorld 1.0.2282.

</description>
  <supportedVersions>
    <li>1.0</li>
  </supportedVersions>
</ModMetaData>